FRANCISCO VARGAS VEGA

Veterinarian - Statistics - Data Science +56 9 75750963 | franciscoalberto.vargas.vega@gmail.com | <u>LinkedIn</u> | <u>GitHub</u>

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Veterinarian undergrad and Masters in Statistics. I have more than 6 years of accumulated experience in Aquaculture, Veterinary Clinical Trials, Data Analysis, Statistics and Market Research, . Competent in salmon weight/feed projections and health, scientific studies designs, and epidemiological, fish production and pharmaceutical market data.

Autonomous, assertive and analytical with a focus in delivering high quality and clean results. Soft skills based on active listening and effective communication. Great ability to adapt to changes in products and projects according to new requirements. Strong capacity for strategic data analysis, either under clear objectives and standards, as well as under exploratory conditions. I've great interest in deepening my knowledge in statistics, data science, biostatistics, epidemiology and health economics.

EXPERIENCE

Data Management Analyst

June 2022 – Today

IQVIA - Information Technology • Programming and analysis of Market Research studies.

Santiago, Chile

Programming in R, PHP and JavaScript, as well as analyzing market research studies for the pharmaceutical industry. Development of tools using JavaScript to improve user experience; creating, implementing and executing IT tools to centralize payment information for study participants, as well as training the Data Management team in R, Excel and PHP.

- Reduction of payment information gathering and processing efforts, from manual processing to automated storage.
- Reduction of client waiting time from 3-5 days to 1 for customized solutions, via personalized service using PHP and JavaScript.
- Training the Data Management Chile in data analysis and data wrangling and automated reports using Excel and R, as well as basic PHP programming

Clinical Trials Assistant Ju

VIRBAC - Pharmaceutical • Coordination of Veterinary Clinical Trials

June 2021 – May 2022

Santiago, Chile

Responsible for writing, developing and implementation of the base internal documentation of the department through SOPs and manuals. Coordination of experimental phases in clinical trials with external and internal CROs. On-site monitoring of veterinary clinical trials and follow-up of the different phases.

- Autonomous implementation of the department documentation.
- In charge of data migration from server to GCP, as well as organizing all internal documents and creating procedural documentation related to fish health evaluations.

Salt-Water Site Assistant

MOWI CHILE S.A. - Aquaculture

September 2019 – January 2021

Puerto Montt, Chile

Responsible for the overall operations and running the assigned Salt-Water site, as well as creating daily data reports and weekly operational requirements.

- Responsible for feeding and weight projections, operational requirements, and legal on-site documentation.
- In charge of on-site salmon harvest procedures, documentation, site traceability and the Health and Safety Programme.
- Responsible for performing necropsies, sea-lice counting and analyzing the site's mortality trends.

Salt-Water Site Assistant

MULTI X - Aquaculture

June 2018 — September 2019

Puerto Montt, Chile

Responsible for the daily fish feeding overall operations, creating daily, weekly and monthly feeding data reports, and weekly operational requirements.

- In charge of keeping the site's legal documentation updated and in check.
- Responsible for keeping the site's Health and Safety Programme and its internal registry updated and clear.
- Responsible of daily salmon feeding, daily and weekly production reports, and weight/feed projections.

Salt-Water Site Assistant

Aquachile S.A. - Aquaculture

Responsible for coordination and administrative processes related to closing both sites in parallel.

• Responsible for coordinating the different services and processes related to the opening of a site, as well as preparing the site for receiving smolts (net-pens, cameras, mortality processing and feed).

ACADEMIC BACKGROUND

Master in Statistics	2023 – 2024 (in progress)
Pontificia Universidad Católica de Chile	Santiago, Chile
Diploma in Biostatistics Pontificia Universidad Católica de Chile	2022 – 2022 Santiago, Chile
Veterinary Medicine	2011 – 2016
Universidad Mayor	Santiago, Chile

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Certifications — Courses — Activities:

- Geovet Congress 2016: Spatial epidemiology, spatial statistics and GIS applications in Veterinary Health.
- Statistical Modeling and Data Science UC 2024: Time series, spatial statistics and uncertainty quantification
- National Congress of the Chilean Statistics Society invited as speaker 2024: Geostatistics, Bayesian statistics, Biostatistics and Epidemiology

Languages:

• English - Native, C2 on IELTS - 2019.

Software — Technologies:

- Microsoft Excel Advanced
- R Advanced
 - Data Cleaning / Wrangling: dplyr, data.table, base R
 - Data Base usage: SQL, duckdb, DBI
 - Data Visualization: ggplot2, shiny, plotly, highcharter, base R
 - Data Modeling: GLMs, non-parametric statistical models, M. Learning, time series and bayesian statistics
 - Model frameworks: h2o, sparklyR and tidymodels as main frameworks
 - Reproducible research using Quarto / RMarkdown
 - Web Scraping
 - R code profiling and optimization
- LaTex, Python, SQL, Power BI Intermediate
- JavaScript, HTML, CSS, PHP, Git Basic